MIKE TSOU

■ mikeytsou@gmail.com (626) 278-6737 San Francisco Bay Area

✓ miketsouin miketsou♠ mikeytsou

SUMMARY

I'm a Web Developer with a Communications degree and experience with data collection and analysis relating to market research strategies. My passion for programming stems from my love for all things tech. My primary focus is to build web applications with the latest technologies and work with a company that will enable me to grow and develop my skills.

SKILLS

LANGUAGES: Ruby, JavaScript, HTML5, CSS3, PostgreSQL, MongoDB FRAMEWORKS/LIBRARIES: Ruby on Rails, Express, React, Redux, jQuery, Ajax, Semantic UI, Bootstrap, Git

PROJECTS

PORTFOLIO (CLICK TO VIEW)

Oct 2017 - Oct 2017

My personal website detailing my background, skills, projects, and my contact information.

Tech Stack: HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, jQuery

EFEEDBACK (CLICK TO VIEW)

Aug 2017 - Sep 2017

A MERN stack application that allows users to send out bulk email surveys to collect some amount of feedback from their customers.

Tech Stack: Node, Express, Passport, MongoDB, Mongoose, Stripe API, SendGrid API, React, Redux, React Router

MYBLOGGER (CLICK TO VIEW)

Jul 2017 - Jul 2017

A blogging app that allows users to create blog entries as well as read and comment on other users blog entries.

Tech Stack: Node, Express, Passport, Quill, MongoDB, Mongoose, HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript

DAILY HABITS (CLICK TO VIEW)

Jun 2017 - Jun 2017

A journaling application that allows users to keep track of their daily activities and see their weekly progress/statistics via web browser or texting with a mobile device.

Tech Stack: Ruby on Rails, JavaScript, React Native, HTML5, CSS3, Twilio API, Google Maps API, Weather Underground API, PostgreSQL

CRABALICIOUS FILMS (CLICK TO VIEW)

Jun 2017 - Jun 2017

A web application that allows users to rate and review films, comment on other users reviews, and sort by categories.

Tech Stack: Ruby on Rails, HTML5, CSS3, Bootstrap, PostgreSQL

EMPLOYMENT

NETPOP Project Manager

San Francisco

• Managing and contributing to the daily execution processes of design, programming, quality control, data collecting/processing, analysis, and production.

- Oversee employees, translators, and 3rd party vendors for qualitative and quantitative market research studies relating to user experience, customer satisfaction, and product development.
- Successful launch of projects by meeting deadlines, hitting targeted quotas, and developing team dynamics.

FARMERS INSURANCE

Los Angeles Sep 2008 - Dec 2009

Insurance Agent

Customer Service

• Selling life, property and casualty, health, automotive, and other types of insurance policies.

- Perform administrative tasks such as maintaining records and handling policy renewals.
- Calculate premiums and establish payment methods.
- Averaged three clients a week making cold calls and generating leads.

ORINDA COUNTRY CLUB

Apr 2007 - May 2008

Provide service for all club members needing assistance.

- Running errands around the area for the pro shop.
- Clean and store members property for their next arrival.
- Set up and run tournaments.

EDUCATION

San Francisco State University
Bachelor of Arts Communications 2012

Dev Bootcamp

18 week immersive web development bootcamp

Orinda